# **Sufyan Saleem**

Address: Phase 6, Sector F8, Street 4, House 425, Hayatabad, Peshawar

Website: <a href="https://sufyansaleem-ec183e.netlify.app/">https://sufyansaleem-ec183e.netlify.app/</a>

Email: sufyansalim94@gmail.com Mobile: +923139243550

### **OBJECTIVE**

I am a 24 years old Software Engineer who loves to play with different technologies. I am looking forward for a promising technical job where I will be subjected to new developmental areas with friendly environment for learning and emerging of my own personality with professional and in time work.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Linknbit Software Engineer Islamabad Pakistan Jan 2019 – present Working for Software Development and IT Solutions Agency. My main roles include developing Websites, Web Applications and Hybrid Mobile Applications. Jan 2019 – present Global Aviation System I am working on parts of backend Node JS, Express, For Central African Republic Swagger, Sequelize cli & Azure In Development **Dynasty Unleashed Models** Developed part of Front-End Modeling agency App for Fashion in React/React-Native & part of designers and marketers Deployment to Firebase & Users can register, create profile, add

### Dokkani.co

User can register, select products, add products to cart.
User add products to wish list and checkout.
Project was abandoned on last stage

Ecommerce Mobile App.

people and hire models at will

 Project was abandoned on last stage due to funds not provided and outsourced to someone else.

My Version

#### Yogurt App

 Step-by-step guide to home crafted authentic Yogurt and Kefir. Take the directions on your phone. Make Yogurt and Kefir at home and communicate.

#### **SmartsAid**

NGO App for refuges

Google Play

React/React-Native, Expo,
Redux, Node JS, Rest API,

Word Press API,

Woo Commerce API, Native Base

Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native, Expo, Native Base

React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Firebase, Rest API, React Native Elements

2018 - FYP Currency Recognition & Conversion Android, Java, Open CV, Rest API, MATLAB Developed an app where users can scan currency note and it will tell which currency it is and how much is it and show the exchange rate in USD. 2014 - 2018 Content Management Systems Java, C#, MSSQL Gym - Point of Sale PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL 2010 RuneScape RPG Java Created bot script for the game called RuneScape. The bot played the game Portfolio Projects DevCamper API HTML, NodeJS, Express,

Bootcamps API

• One can register as a User or Publisher and login also.

• Publisher can create Bootcamps.

 Admin and Publisher can add courses and perform various CRUD operations.

 Users can comment on Bootcamps and update their profile, add picture, and reset password.

DevConnector

Social Media for developers where users register.

 Create profile, create posts, add comments and like and unlike them. React, Redux, CSS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, NodeJS, Heroku

Mongoose,

Injection

MongoDB, Node mailer,

Security for XSS and NOSQL

SmartBrain

• Smart Brain an app with face Recognition.

 Users can register, login and submit images via URL.

 The AI recognizes the face in the picture and draw a border around.

 It works only for one face in the image. React, Redux, CSS, PostgreSQL, Knex, Express, Nodejs, Heroku, Netlify

## **EDUCATION**

Internet of things and AI Specialist Course

PIAIC, Islamabad (2019 - present)

BS in Software Engineering, cgpa 2.78

Institute of Managements Sciences, Peshawar (2014 – 2018)

F.Sc - Pre-Engineering, grade B

ICMS College System Peshawar (2012 – 2014)

Racines School System, Peshawar (2010 – 2012)

## **SPECIALITY AND KNOWLEDGE**

### **Specialities**

Mobile/Hybrid App Developer Web Developer

### **Social Links**









### Knowledge

React/React-Native, Redux, Expo JS, Node JS, Express Mongoose, Sequelize Firebase, Mongo DB HTML, CSS Git, Heroku Rest, GraphQL, MVC Rust Word press, Android Studio, Adobe PS

# **LANGUAGES AND HOBBIES**

### Languages

English Urdu Pashto

### **Hobbies**

Programming, Music, Movies, Video Games, Reading, Hiking, Bodybuilding,